DIMITRA GIANTSIDI

https://dgiantsidi.github.io/ · dimitra.giantsidi@gmail.com Informatics Forum 1.05, University of Edinburgh 10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

I like to build robust and efficient distributed systems!

I am a final year PhD student at the University of Edinburgh, UK and as part of my research, I have worked on some interesting projects: a secure distributed transactional store (Trusted Execution Environments, RDMA and RocksDB), a shielded direct I/O network library for secure replication (Crash Fault Tolerance and BFT) and a fast shared log for serverless computing infrastuctures (byte addressable storage, gRPC/TCP). I am currently designing a trusted NIC architecture for large-scale distributed systems based on SmartNICs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ICSA, University of Edinburgh, UK

June 2023 - now

Research Assistant

- \cdot Implementation of an RDMA-based smartNIC architecture for improved security guarantees.
- \cdot Design and optimization of robust networking protocols for fault tolerance.

Condidential Computing Group, Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

 $Research\ Scientist\ Intern$

 \cdot Design and implementation of a single-node KV store resilient to timing-attacks.

Cloud RnD, Intracom Telecom, Athens, Greece

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

Software & Systems Engineer

· Performance and energy optimization of NFV services.

Unversity of Edinburgh, UK and TUM, Germany

Sept 2019 - present

Thesis advisor and Teaching Assistant

- · Operating Systems, Distributed Computing, Parallel Architectures, Object-oriented Programming.
- · Supervised five BSc/MSc students on their BSc Thesis on Distributed and Networking systems.

EDUCATION

University of Edinburgh, UK

Sept 2019 - present

PhD in Informatics (ICSA): Distributed systems, systems security, replication protocols

- · Sponsors: Microsoft Research, UK Rise, Advisor: Pramod Bhatotia
- · Design of robust distributed data management systems leveraging trusted hardware and byte-addressable storage.

University of Edinburgh, UK

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

MSc in Computer Science: Software engineering, computer systems & high-performance computing

· Thesis: Rollback-Resilient Transaction Protocols using Trusted Counters (Best Performing Female MSc Student Award)

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

Sept 2012 - Feb 2018

Diploma (5-year joint degree, BEng and MEng) in Electrical & Computer Engineering

· Thesis: Improving QoS in modern multi-core servers with Dynamic Cache Partitioning

PUBLICATIONS

Anchor: Secure Persistent Memory Architecture, SIGMOD'24

Dimitris Stravakakis, Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Philip Saendig, Shady Issa, Pramod Bhatotia.

FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing, ACM HPDC'23

 $\label{eq:continuity} \mbox{Dimitra Giantsidi, Emmanouil Giortamis, Nathaniel Tornow, Florin Dinu, Pramod Bhatotia.}$

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions, IEEE/IFIP DSN'22 (Best paper nominee)

Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Natacha Crooks, Pramod Bhatotia.

Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System, USENIX ATC'21

Maurice Bailleu, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasilis Gavrielatos, Le Quoc Do, Vijay Nagarajan, Pramod Bhatotia.

DICER: Diligent Cache Partitioning for Efficient Workload Consolidation, ICPP'21

Konstantinos Nikas, Nikela Papadopoulou, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasileios Karakostas, Georgios I Goumas, Nectarios Koziris.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Bash, Golang, Java, Vitis HLS

Systems Programming RocksDB and folly libraries, TEEs (Intel SGX, OpenEnclave SDK, AMD-sev),

direct network I/O (DPDK, RDMA, Alveo SmartNICs), SPDK,

Intel RDT, LLVM, collectd, POSIX/Unix, OpenMP and MPI, gRPC

Virtualization KVM, Qemu/Libvirt, Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control

Git

Distributed Programming Hadoop MapReduce, Socket and RPC programming